

Akash Bhatia

Senior Data Engineer

How to reach me:

Cell:

9971735084

Email:

akashbhatia92@gmail.com

Linkedin:

linkedin.com/in/akash-bhatia-17aa1784

Adress:

3E-133 N.I.T. Faridabad, Haryana 121001

Certifications:

Azure DP-100

Neo4j Graph Database Developer

Professional Skills

Coding Languages:

Pyspark, R, SQL ,HTML/CSS, Python

Frameworks/Technologies:

Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, Neural Network, Flask, TensorFlow, Pytorch

Personal Profile

MBA Graduate and full time Data Engineer with passion for Data Practices. Proven experience in creating and designing Data Science/ Engineering solutions.

Highly experienced Data Scientist with over 5 years' experience in Data Extraction, Data Modelling, Statistical Modeling, Data Mining, Machine Learning and Data Visualization, Natural Language Processing (NLP) using modern architectures with CI/CD pipelining

Educational

Niit University

MBA in Data Science

- Attended from 2018 to 2020
- Taking up specialization courses in data science to broaden skill set
- Worked as an intern in Coforge Technologies for 2 Years

MDU, Rohtak

B.Tech in Electronics and Communication Engineering

- Attended from July. 2010 to June 2014
- Conducted Workshops on Robotics and Embedded Systems

Tools:

Pycharm, Jupyter Notebook, Git, Denodo Express, PowerBI, Tableau, PostGre SQL, JIRA, SVN, AWS Elastic Container

Career Summary

Senior Data Engineer

Coforge Technologies Aug 2018 to present

- Created various statistical models, performed Hypothesis testing, Principal Component Analysis, Factor Analysis, Cluster Analysis, Discriminant Analysis on customer data.
- Worked on review segmentation and prioritize using NLP libraries
- Worked on price suggestion of used and refurbished product using gradient Boosting algorithms
- Worked on Customer Predictive Lifetime Value Modelling
- Worked on K- Means clustering for customer segmentation.

Senior Associate

Nagarro Softwares Dec. 2017 to July 2018

- Created multiple regression models like ElasticNet, XGB Regressor
- Created PowerBI Dashboards and Reporting for European Banks
- Worked on Creating Data Virtualization using Denodo Software for multiple Data Sources integration

Software Engineer

InterGlobe Technologies Aug. 2014 to Dec. 2017

- Created Customer
 Segmentation Models for
 E-commerce Platform
- Ad-hoc analysis on Python to implement client request and present reports in PowerBi.

Character References

Ankur Srivastava

Team Lead, Incedo Technologies Cell: 8447768015

Pankaj Madaan

SAS Developer, EXL Services Cell: 8700460383